# **Soroush Chehresa**

Front-End Software Engineer

Location: Tehran, Iran

**Contact**: (+98) 930 998 6367 **Email**: <u>s1996ch@gmail.com</u>

Website: <a href="https://soroush.js.org">https://soroush.js.org</a>

GitHub: https://github.com/soroushchehresa

#### **ABOUT**

An enthusiastic front-end software engineer with more than 7 years of experience in the field. during the last five years, from front-end to mobile to desktop to back-end I have experience of developing a lot of applications using modern JavaScript frameworks and libraries. as a developer who thrives in agile teams, I have worked successfully with product owners, developers, and designers to achieve successful implementations.

#### **SKILLS**

JavaScript (ES6+), TypeScript, React, React Native, Vue, Next.js, Nuxt.js, Redux, Vuex, Redux-Saga, Electron, Tailwind CSS, Styled-Components, Node, Express, Socket IO, Webpack, GraphQL, Docker, Jest, Enzyme, TDD, BDD, MySQL, Redis, SASS, HTML5, CSS3

### **EXPERIENCE**

## JavaScript Engineer at Sabaldea

Dec 2017 - Present — Tehran, Iran — Full-time

- Migrate old multi-page web app for smart TVs to SPA using React and increate its performance by 30%.
- ▶ Propose and implement scalable solutions to issues with TVs' web browsers and low-performance devices.
- ▶ Develop a web SDK and an admin panel for the push notification service using TypeScript and Next.js.
- Build and ship Tizen apps for Samsung smart TVs using React Native.
- Create an internal mobile app to see campaigns reports through charts using React Native.
- Communicate on a daily basis with agile teams of engineers, designers, and customer care.

## Front-End Engineer at KeyLead Health

Aug 2020 - Jan 2021 — Remote — Part-time

Worked closely with product owners, designers, and other developers to create and manage some mobile apps and its web services for seizure and diabetes patients using React Native, Node, and TypeScript, as well as an admin panel for managing the underlying processes using Nuxt.js and TypeScript.

## Front-End Engineer at Peaksview

Dec 2017 - May 2018 — Remote — Part-time

- Implemented a mobile application as manager of Peaksview's urban displays through Bluetooth using React Native, as well as an admin panel for managing the underlying processes using React and Next.js.
- ► Interfaced with user experience designers and other developers to ensure thoughtful and coherent user experiences across Peaksview's iOS and Android mobile apps.

## Front-End Engineer at Hampa

Jun 2017 - Dec 2017 — Tehran, Iran — Full-time

- Collaborated with a small team of young experienced developers to implement and ship a highly interactive and cross-platform mobile application using React Native.
- Participated with other developers to implement an administration panel to monitor and manage the application and its underlying processes using React and GraphQL.

## Front-End Engineer at Asiatech

Jul 2016 - May 2017 — Tehran, Iran — Full-time

- Interviewer of front-end developers and coached front-end interns.
- Developed some single page web applications for clients using Angular.js.
- Engineered and maintained major features of an online real-time game website using JavaScript.
- Collaborated with agile teams of developers and designers to implement the new version of Asiatech's main website using WordPress.

## Front-End Developer at Nikanwp

Oct 2015 - Apr 2016 — Tehran, Iran — Full-time

Worked closely with product owners, designers, and other developers to create some websites for clients such as <u>Webpoosh</u>, <u>Ertebateamn</u>, <u>SDS-TC</u>, <u>Payagene Biotech</u>, <u>Vinehsaar</u>, and etc using WordPress, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, and jQuery.

## Front-End Developer at Web NITC

May 2015 - Oct 2015 — Tehran, Iran — Full-time

Participated with other developers and designers to build some websites for clients such as <u>Sepehr Electric</u>,
OEES, <u>Fanabgostar</u>, <u>Kianpolymer</u>, and etc using their own CMS, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, and jQuery.

## Front-End Developer at Freelancer

Oct 2013 - May 2015 — Tehran, Iran — Part-time

Through online advertising, I was able to obtain some projects from some small companies and stores in Iran and I developed some websites for them using Joomla, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, and jQuery.

### **OPEN-SOURCE PROJECTS**

- Unsplash Wallpapers (Electron, React, Redux, Flow)
- Vue SoundCloud (Vue, Nuxt.js, Vuex)
- Awesome Coronavirus (Node, TypeScript, Ejs)
- ► Giant Sur (React, Next.js, Tailwind, TypeScript)
- GitHub Readme LinkedIn (Node, TypeScript)
- Clubhouse Unfollowers (React, Redux, TypeScript)
- Coronavirus CLI (Node, TypeScript)
- Axios React (React, TypeScript)

### **EDUCATION**

### Web Design Methodology (JavaScript)

Tehran Institute of Technology (MFT)

### Web Design Foundation (HTML5, CSS3)

Tehran Institute of Technology (MFT)

### Diploma — Computer Science

Shahid Sadoughi Featured Public Vocational School